BRETT STINSON

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

◆ LA MESA, CA, UNITED STATES

◆ +13233668410

• DETAILS •

La Mesa, CA
United States
+13233668410
brett.stinson727@gmail.com

LINKS

Brett Stinson | LinkedIn

SKILLS

JavaScript

Node.js

Redux

React

Vue

Angular

Svelte

Typescript

Happy.js

Java

Spring Boot

PHP

Python

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

Tailwindcss

Git

Docker

MongoDB

MySQL

PostgreSQL

PROFILE

Experienced Full stack Web Developer with 10 years of experience in many stages of advanced web development, especially in JavaScript based development stacks such as MERN, MEVN and MEAN.

Proficient in other web development languages like Python(4 years), PHP(5 years), Java-(5 years), Ruby(3 years) and bunch of frameworks and libraries based on these languages (CI, Laravel, Symfony, Spring Boot, Ruby on Rails, Django ...).

Equipped with important skill-sets for being a perfect web developer such as DB skills(-MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MongoDB ...) and cloud services like Amazon, Google and Azure.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full Stack Developer at BlueGrace Logistics, Chicago, IL, USA

August 2018 — February 2023

- Spearheaded a cross-functional team of 8 developers in upgrading legacy system to modern tech stack; reduced system downtime by 40% and improved overall efficiency by 25%.
- Migrated application to cloud-based infrastructure and optimized database queries; reduced time-to-market by 40% and decreased server costs by 35%.
- Revamped the front-end of the company's web platform using Next.js and React, improving the user interface and experience, ultimately increasing customer engagement by 30%.
- Architected and executed a complete automated deployment process for a new architecture based on micro-service, reducing deployment time from 2 hours to 10 minutes and enabling seamless scaling of the application.
- Main technologies: Puppeteer, Storybook, Jest, Material UI, Styled-components, GraphQL, TailwindCSS, Happy.js, Apollo, React Router, Redux, React.js, Typescript, Node.js, Next.js, Spring Boot, AWS EC2, Lambda, S3, DynamoDB

Full Stack Developer at KickFin, Austin, TX, USA

February 2017 — July 2018

- Optimized private APIs by refactoring and streamlining code base; reduced API response time by 50% and saved 10+ hours per week on troubleshooting and maintenance tasks.
- Eliminated 20+ UI bugs and improved app functionality by conducting comprehensive testing, reducing user complaints by 50% and improving overall user satisfaction.
- Main technologies: React.js, Amazon Web Services (AWS), MongoDB, Spring Boot

Front-end Developer at Beats by Dre, Santa Monica, CA, USA

March 2016 — January 2017

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to rebuild the front-end of the company's key product with React and Redux that increased user satisfaction by 45%.
- Developed a new UI/UX design and fashioned CSS and boosted mobile traffic by 30%.
- Replied with near immediate updates to requested changes from the Dr. Dre project manager keeping over 90% of deadlines and applying 99% of user requirements.
- Main technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Redux

Web Developer at Rikkeisoft, Osaka, Japan

July 2013 — March 2016

- Developed 15+ web applications from scratch with PHP based frameworks (Laravel, Symfony), Node.js and React with more than 90% of project success rate.
- Updated and maintained 10+ web applications built with PHP frameworks and React+Redux that achieved great user satisfaction increment and fixed more than 95% of bugs issued.
- Main technologies : Java, PHP, Laravel, Symfony, Javascript, Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Bootstrap, MySQL, MS SQL, MongoDB, Oracle

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree of Computer Science and System Engineering, Kobe University, Kobe April 2009 — March 2013

Received a bachelor degree of Computer Science and System Engineering